<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- name="GENERATOR" content="github.com/mmarkdown/mmark Mmark Markdown Processor - mmark.miek.nl" -->
<rfc version="3" ipr="trust200902" docName="draft-sitw-dnsop-metazones-01" submissionType="independent" category="info" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" indexInclude="false">

<front>
<title abbrev="metazones">DNS Metazones</title><seriesInfo value="draft-sitw-dnsop-metazones-01" stream="independent" status="informational" name="Internet-Draft"></seriesInfo>
<author role="editor" initials="S." surname="Instenes" fullname="Shawn Instenes"><organization></organization><address><postal><street></street>
</postal><email>shawn@instenes.com </email>
</address></author><author role="editor" initials="T." surname="Wicinski" fullname="Tim Wicinski"><organization></organization><address><postal><street></street>
<city>Elkins</city>
<code>26241</code>
<country>USA</country>
<region>WV</region>
</postal><email>tjw.ietf@gmail.com</email>
</address></author><date/>
<area></area>
<workgroup>DNSOP</workgroup>

<abstract>
<t>This document describes a method for automatic zone catalog
 provisioning and synchronization among DNS primary and secondary
 nameservers by storing and transferring the catalogs as regular DNS
 zones.</t>
</abstract>

</front>

<middle>

<section anchor="introduction"><name>Introduction</name>
<t>DNS nameservers implement AXFR and IXFR for zone data synchronization
 among a zone's primary its and secondary nameservers, but the list of
 zones served by the primary (called a catalog in [RFC1035]) is not
 automatically synchronized.  The administrator of a DNS nameserver
 farm has to manually, or via an external application layer,
 synchronize such zone catalogs among primaries and their secondary
 nameservers.  This can be inconvenient, error-prone and dependent on
 the nameserver implementation.</t>
<t>A method for automatic zone catalog provisioning and synchronization
 is useful, so that the zone catalog can be maintained in a reference
 location by an administrator, similar to zone data.</t>
<t>This document describes one such method, in which the catalog is
 represented as a regular DNS zone called a &quot;catalog zone&quot;, and
 transferred using DNS zone transfers.  The representation of catalogs
 within DNS zones is specified and nameserver requirements are listed
 so that DNS implementations can support catalog zones.</t>
<t>The contents and representation of catalog zones are described in
 Section 2.  Nameserver behavior is described in Section 3.  A
 glossary of some terms used in this memo is provided in Appendix A.</t>
</section>

</middle>

<back>

</back>

</rfc>
